They took your data. Then they took control.
The Great Hack is a documentary film directed by Karim Amer.
Data—arguably the world’s most valuable asset—is being
weaponized to wage cultural and political wars.
The dark world of data exploitation is uncovered through the unpredictable, personal journeys of
players on different sides of the explosive Cambridge Analytica/Facebook data story.
Self - Former Dir. of Business Development, Cambridge
Analytica, played by Brittany Kaiser.
Self - Associate Professor Parsons School of Design, played by David Carroll.
Self - Founder @PersonalDataIO, played by Paul-Olivier Dehaye.
Self - Data Rights Solicitor, played by Ravi Naik.
Self - Former COO/CFO Cambridge Analytica/SCL, played by Julian Wheatland.
Self - Investigative Journalist for The Guardian, played by Carole Cadwalladr.
The Great Hack is a 2019 documentary film about the Facebook–Cambridge Analytica data scandal, produced and directed by Jehane
Noujaim and Karim Amer, both previous documentary Academy Award nominees (The Square, Control Room, Startup.com).
The film's music was composed by Emmy-nominated film composer Gil Talmi.
The Great Hack premiered at the 2019 Sundance Film Festival in the Documentary
Premieres section and was released by Netflix on July 24, 2019.
The documentary focuses on David Carroll of Parsons and The New School, Brittany Kaiser (former business
development director for Cambridge Analytica), and British investigative journalist Carole Cadwalladr.
Their stories interweave to expose the work of Cambridge Analytica in the politics of various
countries, including the United Kingdom's Brexit campaign and the 2016 United States elections.
The film explores themes of propaganda, politics, united
kingdom, social network, behavior modification.
The tone is dark.